

CONTACT ME AT

- alrobwilloliver@gmail.com
- www.alanoliver.dev
- www.linkedin.com/in/alanoliver-3a28aa118/

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Full Stack Development
- Node JS
- Golang
- Git
- Vue JS
- React JS
- MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB
- Heroku
- International Communication
- ESL Teaching

AWARDS RECEIVED

- Outstanding Student Awards Mandarin Scholarship Spring
 and Summer Semesters (2018)
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (2016)
- Year Group Best English Student (2016)

ALAN OLIVER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & EDUCATOR

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software developer with over 2 years experience, now working for a Blockchain company in Node JS and Golang building APIs on the backend. Prior, I have over 4 years professional experience teaching English at all ages, mostly adults.

In my spare time I enjoy learning about monetary policy, speaking Mandarin Chinese and travelling.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

Cudo Ventures | March 2021 - present

- Develop new features on and maintain existing API.
- Contribute to backend microservice infrastructure in Golang and Node.js.
- Implement tests for software to ensure reliability.

Junior Developer

New Verve Consulting | August 2020 - March 2021

- Develop features for an Atlassian Marketplace app.
- Implement tests for software to ensure reliability.

Oral English Teacher

North Eastern Accounting and Finance University, Shandong, China | September 2018 - July 2020

- Develop curriculum for students in English, Finance and Tourism majors.
- Give lectures and lead classes.
- Examine students on their exam and performance.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

HuaZhong University of Science and Technology

HSK 4 | Sep 2017 - June 2018

 Studied Mandarin listening, reading, speaking and writing at an intermediate level.

University of Hull

BA Politics and History | Sep 2013 - June 2016

- 2:1
- Subjects included International Relations Theory, Political Philosophy, Counter Terrorism and Free Speech.
- Dissertation focussed on the Mongol military conquests and the political, social and economic impact in the Middle East regions of Persia.